<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p class="v2-structure-link"><b>Message Structure:</b> <a href="StructureDefinition-OUL_R23.html">OUL_R23</a></p>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This message was designed to accommodate specimen oriented testing. It should be applicable to, for example, laboratory automation systems requiring container.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Generally this construct allows <strong>transfer of multiple results related to one or more specific containers with one or more specimens from a patient.</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In addition to the patient results themselves it permits the communication of the following kinds of information:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Analysis results of a non patient related sample (e.g., environmental) – patient related segments (e.g., PID, PD1, PV1, PV2) are optional.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Analysis results to a particular container with QC sample and the lot and manufacturer information about this sample (SAC-INV segments).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Basic identification data (lot, manufacturer, etc.) of the reagents and other substances involved in the generation of analysis results (TCD-SID segments).</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Refer to Chapter 13 Laboratory Automation for additional examples of usage of SAC.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Device segment (DEV) provides additional device information for a device referenced in one or more of the PRT segments in the message (using PRT-10 Participation Device to match DEV-2 Unique Device Identifier or PRT-22 Participation Device Type using DEV-3 Device Type).</p>
</div>
<div id="v2-ack-content" style="display:none;">
<table class="grid">
<thead><tr><th>Mode</th><th>Response</th></tr></thead>
<tbody>
<tr><td>Original Mode</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-ACK-R23.html">ACK^R23</a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Enhanced Mode: Immediate</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-ACK-R23.html">ACK^R23</a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Enhanced Mode: Application</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-ACK-R23.html">ACK^R23</a></td></tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
