<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The A09 and A10 - patient arriving-tracking events are used when there is a change in a patient&#8217;s physical location (inpatient or outpatient) and when this is NOT a change in the official census bed location, as in the case of an outpatient setting. There are three situations that qualify as non-census location changes: (a) patient tracking, (b) the patient is in transit between locations for some time, (c) a notification of temporary location change.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Patient tracking: This can be used when the nursing application sends a "transfer" before the Patient Administration (or official census) system issues an A02 (transfer a patient) event. If the patient has left for a non-temporary location and is not in transit, then the <em>PV1-3 - Assigned Patient Location</em> must contain the new patient location, while <em>PV1-6 - Prior Patient Location</em> must contain the old patient location.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In transit: The patient&#8217;s location during the time between an A09 and an A10 (patient arriving - tracking) is defined as "in transit." The A09 event is sent when a patient departs from one area of the healthcare facility for the purpose of arriving at another area, but without leaving the healthcare institution. This event is used when there is a time span during which the patient is neither at his/her old location nor at his/her new location. This process can take some time if a patient is being sent to another area in a multi-campus or multi-facility environment. The combination of an A09 and an A10 would serve the same purpose as an A02 (transfer a patient) event, except that it accounts for a gap in time required for transport between facilities. If the patient will be in transit during the time between the A09 (patient departing - tracking) event and the A10 (patient arriving - tracking) event, then <em>PV1-42 - Pending Location</em> is used for the new location, and <em>PV1-11 - Temporary Location</em> and <em>PV1-43 - Prior Temporary Location</em> would not be used. <em>PV1-6 - Prior Patient Location</em> should be used for the old location.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Temporary location: An A09 can also be used when the patient is being sent to a temporary location (such as the O/R, X-RAY, LIMBO, or HALLWAY). The patient may or may not return to the same assigned location after occupying the temporary location. If the patient is going to a temporary location (such as the O/R, X-RAY, LIMBO, or HALLWAY), then <em>PV1-11 - Temporary Location</em> is used to indicate the new temporary location. If the patient is moving from one temporary location to another, then <em>PV1-43 - Prior Temporary Location</em> may also be used. <em>PV1-6 - Prior Patient Location</em> and <em>PV1-11 - Temporary Location</em> should be used when the patient is moving from a permanent location to a temporary location.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The fields included when this message is sent should be the fields pertinent to communicate this event. When other important fields change, it is recommended that the A08 (update patient information) event be used in addition.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Attention: The DG1 segment was retained for backward compatibility only as of v2.4</strong> and was withdrawn and removed from this message structure as of v2.7.</p>
</div>
<div id="v2-classic-content" style="display:none;">
<p>The full structure definition for <a href="StructureDefinition-ADT_A09-A.html">ADT_A09</a> is available on its own page.</p>
<table class="grid">
<thead><tr><th>Segment</th><th>Description</th><th>Status</th></tr></thead>
<tbody>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation"><a href="StructureDefinition-MSH.html">MSH</a></td><td>Message Header</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation">[{ <a href="StructureDefinition-ARV.html">ARV</a> }]</td><td>Access Restrictions</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation">[{ <a href="StructureDefinition-SFT.html">SFT</a> }]</td><td>Software Segment</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation">[ <a href="StructureDefinition-UAC.html">UAC</a> ]</td><td>User Authentication Credential</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation"><a href="StructureDefinition-EVN.html">EVN</a></td><td>Event Type</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation"><a href="StructureDefinition-PID.html">PID</a></td><td>Patient Identification</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation">[ <a href="StructureDefinition-PD1.html">PD1</a> ]</td><td>Additional Demographics</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation">[{ <a href="StructureDefinition-GSP.html">GSP</a> }]</td><td>Person Gender and Sex</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation">[{ <a href="StructureDefinition-GSR.html">GSR</a> }]</td><td>Recorded Gender and Sex</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation">[{ <a href="StructureDefinition-GSC.html">GSC</a> }]</td><td>Sex Parameter for Clinical Use</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation"><a href="StructureDefinition-PV1.html">PV1</a></td><td>Patient Visit</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation">[ <a href="StructureDefinition-PV2.html">PV2</a> ]</td><td>Patient Visit - Additional Info.</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation">[{ <a href="StructureDefinition-DB1.html">DB1</a> }]</td><td>Disability Information</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr class="v2-classic-group"><td class="v2-classic-notation">[{ --- Observation begin</td><td></td><td></td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation">   <a href="StructureDefinition-OBX.html">OBX</a></td><td>Observation/Result</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr><td class="v2-classic-notation">   [{ <a href="StructureDefinition-PRT.html">PRT</a> }]</td><td>Participation</td><td>A</td></tr>
<tr class="v2-classic-group"><td class="v2-classic-notation">}] --- Observation end</td><td></td><td></td></tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<div id="v2-ack-content" style="display:none;">
<table class="grid">
<thead><tr><th>Mode</th><th>Response</th></tr></thead>
<tbody>
<tr><td>Original Mode</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-ACK-A09.html">ACK^A09</a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Enhanced Mode: Immediate</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-ACK-A09.html">ACK^A09</a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Enhanced Mode: Application</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-ACK-A09.html">ACK^A09</a></td></tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
