<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p class="v2-structure-link"><b>Message Structure:</b> <a href="StructureDefinition-RDS_O13.html">RDS_O13</a></p>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The RDS message may be created by the pharmacy/treatment application for each instance of dispensing a drug or treatment to fill an existing order or orders. In the most common case, the RDS messages would be routed to a Nursing application or to some clinical application, which needs the data about drugs dispensed or treatments given. As a site-specific variant, the original order segments (RXO, RXE and their associated RXR/RXCs) may be sent optionally (for comparison).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The ORC must have the filler order number and the order control code RE. The RXE and associated RXCs may be present if the receiving application needs any of their data. The RXD carries the dispense data for a given issuance of medication: thus it may describe a single dose, a half-day dose, a daily dose, a refill of a prescription, etc. The RXD is not a complete record of an order. Use the RXO and RXE segments if a complete order is needed. It is a record from the pharmacy or treatment supplier to the Nursing application (or other) with drug/treatment dispense and administration instructions.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The FT1 segment is optional and repeating in order to accommodate multiple charge, benefit and pricing situations. Example use cases demonstrating zero, one and two FT1 segments follow:</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the case where the RDS message represents a dispense event that is in process (i.e., has not been received by the patient), the financial transactions associated with the dispense do not yet exist. Until the financial transactions associated with the dispense event have been completed, no FT1 segment may exist in the message.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the case where the RDS message represents a dispense event that has been received by the patient, and thus all financial transactions have been completed, the RDS message may contain one or more FT1 segments. Examples of single and multiple FT1 segments follow.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Payment for the dispense event completed by a single payor:</p>
</div>
<div class="literalblock er7">
<div class="content">
<pre>MSH|^&amp;~\|Pharm|GenHosp|CIS|GenHosp|2006082911150700||RDS^O13^RDS_O13|...&lt;cr&gt;</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>PID|&#8230;&#8203;&lt;cr&gt;</p>
</div>
<div class="literalblock er7">
<div class="content">
<pre>ORC|RE|...&lt;cr&gt;</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="literalblock er7">
<div class="content">
<pre>RXD|1|00310-0131-10^LISINOPRIL 10MG TABLET^NDC|200607150830|100|TAB|...&lt;cr&gt;</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="literalblock er7">
<div class="content">
<pre>FT1|1|||200607151035||PY|00310-0131-10^LISINOPRIL 10MG TABLET^NDC|||100|125.43&amp;USD|...&lt;cr&gt;</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Payment for the dispense event involves multiple payment sources:</p>
</div>
<div class="literalblock er7">
<div class="content">
<pre>MSH|^&amp;~\|Pharm|GenHosp|CIS|GenHosp|2006082213000700||RDS^O13^RDS_O13|...&lt;cr&gt;</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>PID|&#8230;&#8203;&lt;cr&gt;</p>
</div>
<div class="literalblock er7">
<div class="content">
<pre>ORC|RE|...&lt;cr&gt;</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="literalblock er7">
<div class="content">
<pre>RXD|1|00340-0241-10^VERAPAMIL 120MG TABLET^NDC|200607200940|100|TAB|...&lt;cr&gt;</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="literalblock er7">
<div class="content">
<pre>FT1|1|||200607211055||CD|00340024110^VERAPAMIL 120MG TABLET ^NDC|||100|55.43&amp;USD|...&lt;cr&gt; (amount paid by insurance)</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="literalblock er7">
<div class="content">
<pre>FT1|2|||200607211055||CP|00340024110^VERAPAMIL 120MG TABLET ^NDC|||100|5.00&amp;USD|...&lt;cr&gt; (copay paid by patient)</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<div class="title">Note</div>
</td>
<td class="content">
The use of RDS with the trigger of O01 and RRD with the trigger O02 is maintained for backward compatibility as of v 2.4 <strong><em>and is withdrawn as of v 2.7</em></strong>.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div id="v2-ack-content" style="display:none;">
<table class="grid">
<thead><tr><th>Mode</th><th>Response</th></tr></thead>
<tbody>
<tr><td>Original Mode</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-RRD-O14.html">RRD^O14</a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Enhanced Mode: Immediate</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-ACK-O13.html">ACK^O13</a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Enhanced Mode: Application</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-RRD-O14.html">RRD^O14</a></td></tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
