<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p class="v2-structure-link"><b>Message Structure:</b> <a href="StructureDefinition-MDM_T01-F.html">MDM_T01</a></p>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This is a notification of a cancellation of a document.</p>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<div class="title">Note</div>
</td>
<td class="content">
This trigger event should be used only for an original document with an Availability Status of "Unavailable."
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When a document has been made available for patient care, the process should be to replace the original document, which then becomes obsolete. The replacement document describes why the erroneous information exists.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Scenario:</strong> When the author dictated a document, the wrong patient identification was given, and the document was transcribed and sent to the wrong patient&#8217;s record. When the error is discovered, a cancellation notice is sent to remove the document from general access in the wrong patient&#8217;s record. In these cases, a reason should be supplied in the cancellation message. To protect patient privacy, the correct patient&#8217;s identifying information should not be placed on the erroneous document that is retained in the wrong patient&#8217;s record for historical reference. A new document notification and content will be created using a T02 (original document notification and content) event and sent for association with the correct patient&#8217;s record.</p>
</div>
<div id="v2-ack-content" style="display:none;">
<table class="grid">
<thead><tr><th>Mode</th><th>Response</th></tr></thead>
<tbody>
<tr><td>Original Mode</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-ACK-T11.html">ACK^T11</a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Enhanced Mode: Immediate</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-ACK-T11.html">ACK^T11</a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Enhanced Mode: Application</td><td><a href="StructureDefinition-ACK-T11.html">ACK^T11</a></td></tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
